(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-19T01:19:37.753186",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ひれ伏せ！
Kneel!
もー！
Geez!
ひれ伏せ！
Kneel!
プロデューサー！！！
Producer!!!
どうしたんですか、ラプラスさん
What's the matter, Laplus-san?
次の生誕ライブ、なんにもやることないんですけど！！
I have absolutely nothing to do for my next Birthday Live!
毎年いろいろやってきたけど…
I've done all sorts of things every year, but...
去年は、ミームやりすぎて、ミームキャラになっちゃったし、どうしよう！
last year I went too far with memes and became a meme character! What should I do?!
デビュー当時のアイドルらしさは もう見る影もないですからね
There's no longer even a trace of the idol you were at your debut.
吾輩はどうやっていけば良いんだー
What on earth should I do?!
勝手にTire表とか作っちゃいましたし...
I even went and made a tier list without asking...
それだ！
That's it!
ほら、吾輩お姉さん大好きでしょ？
Look, I love older sisters, right?
？？？？
????
ホロライブのお姉さんを大集合させよう！
Let's gather all the Hololive older sisters!
お姉さんライブだ！！！
An older sisters' live concert!
....
大丈夫だよ！当てはある！！！吾輩に任せとけ！
It's fine! I have a plan! Leave it to me!
それはちゃんとラプラスさんのライブとして成立するんですか？
Will that actually work as a La+ concert?
そこは…なんかいい感じにやるんだよ！
Well... we'll figure something out!
ていうか、吾輩のこと好きなファンならさ、やっぱり吾輩が好きなことしてるところ、楽しく見てくれるんじゃない？！
I mean, fans who like me would surely enjoy watching me do what I love, right?
限度があるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there a limit to that?
とにかく、やるって決めたらやるの！いくぞー！！！
Anyway, once we decide to do it, we do it! Here we go!!!
ノエルさん！
Noel-san!
どうしたの？ラブちゃん？
What's wrong, Lap-chan?
実は、もうすぐ吾輩の生誕ライブがあるんですけど、よかったらノエルさんにも出てほしいなって…
Actually, my birthday live is coming up soon, and I was hoping you could perform with me...
えー！ラブちゃん誘ってくれるの！嬉しい！もちろん、だよ！
What?! You're inviting me, Lap-chan? I'm so happy! Of course!
よーし団長、歌とダンス頑張っちゃおうかな！先輩として、かっこいいところ見せちゃうよー！！！
Alright, I'll do my best at singing and dancing! As your senior, I'll show you my cool side!
あ、いや…歌は吾輩がやるんで…ね？ほら、これ持って！
Ah, no... I'll be doing the singing... Okay? Here, hold this!
え、なに？どういうこと？これってうちわ？
Eh, what? What do you mean? Is this a fan?
さて、あとは何を歌うかですね…
Now, what else should she sing...
一曲目はね、きっとノエルさんも喜んでくれるはず！
For the first song, I'm sure Noel-san will be thrilled!
え、団長が？
Eh, me?
去年からノエルさんの影響からか吾輩のファン層が広がって、こういう曲が喜んでもらえるかなー！って思って！
Since last year, maybe because of your influence, my fanbase has grown, so I thought they'd love a song like this!
えー！期待しちゃうけど…良いのおぉ？
Wow, now I'm getting excited... Is it really okay?!
良いですよー！一曲目、盛り上がっていきましょうー！
Of course! Let's get hyped for the first song!
横画面で開始します
[Starting in horizontal mode]
キター！
It's here!
おっち
O-cchi!
存外見掛け倒しな
An unexpectedly disappointing
虚勢張ってるロマンス
bluff of a romance.
組み替えちゃって遺伝子
Let's recombine our genes.
トゥケトゥケな電波に乗った感情論
A theory of emotion riding on rapid radio waves,
僕のアピール見逃さないでよ
don't miss out on my appeal.
人間なんてだれだってこういうのが好きなんだって
Everyone likes this kind of stuff anyway,
一人よがりオーガズミネーション
a self-indulgent orgasm-nation.
溢れてドヴァドヴァ
Overflowing, gushing out.
年季入りなあざとさ
Vested with calculation,
「好き」の塗りたくり
smeared in "love".
決めるぜ僕の果て
I'll decide my limit.
ラブバリガルバルマンダ
Love Barrier, Garu-Baru-Manda!
膨らんじゃった やばおぴ加減
It's swollen up, this crazy condition.
最高潮のをくれてやる
I'll give you my absolute climax.
好きって言葉で踊って
Dance with the word "love",
迎え撃つから君のアイデンティティティティティーン
and I'll meet your iden-ti-ti-ti-teen!
侮らないで 夢見がちボーイ
Don't underestimate me, dreamy boy.
意外とありなんだって
It's actually quite acceptable.
気づいて妄想フラストレーション
Realize this delusional frustration,
もう暴走止まらない ギガンティック
my rampage won't stop, it's gigantic!
よそ見厳禁 見てててててね
No looking away, look right at me!
ラプちゃん、最高ー！！！
Lap-chan, you're the best!!!
もっと、輝いてくれーー！！！可愛いよぉぉぉー！！！
Shine even brighter!!! You're so cute!!!
３・２・１で目覚めて
Wake up on three, two, one,
恋に落ちたりなんかして
and maybe fall in love.
わし掴んでシークレット
Grab hold of our secret.
あなんだやっぱり単純で
Ah, look how simple it is after all.
僕にとって僕が 揺るぎない絶対王政
For me, my rule is an absolute monarchy.
だからね君だって 僕が大好きでしょ？
So you must love me too, right?
僕だけの領域
My own personal domain,
息遣いドキドキ 優しくして
breathing heavily, heart beating, be gentle.
山盛りなあいうぉんちゅ
Heaps of "I want you".
アガっちゃって恥じらっちゃって
Getting excited, acting shy,
狂っちゃえばイージーモード
going crazy is easy mode.
わんつー
One, two,
とろとろに溶かして愛need you
melt me completely, I need your love.
誤算過ぎた僕のエラートラップ
My miscalculated error trap,
なめないで ここは限界突破ラブゲーム
don't underestimate me, this is a love game breaking limits.
加速しちゃって やばおぴ加減
Accelerating, this crazy condition.
最高潮のをみせてやれ
Show me your absolute climax.
駆け引き上手な僕がルール
I'm skilled at tactics, so I make the rules,
狙い撃ち君をプラマイプラスで
sniping you with a plus-minus-plus.
引き返せない二人だけの秘密
There's no turning back from our secret.
意外とありかもなんて
Maybe it's actually possible,
気づいた？罪作りラブポーション
did you notice? The sinful love potion.
一切合切とめどないギガンティック
Absolutely endless and gigantic,
目移りなんて許さない
I won't let your eyes wander.
ね？
Okay?
おっちとは、ギガンティックO.T.Nの略称であり
O-cchi is an abbreviation of Gigantic O.T.N,
主に救急用のものとして扱われており男女兼用である
it is mainly used for emergency purposes and is unisex.
最近では…あ、ちょ、間違えた！
Recently... Ah, wait, I messed up!
頑張って！
Hang in there!
種類の…おっち…救急的であって…ラストの…えー…
type of... O-cchi... emergency... last... uh...
あー、もう！何言ってんのか、さっぱりわかんねえ！
Ah, jeez! I have no idea what I'm saying!
あー、全く、全く、わかんねえ！
Ah, absolutely, absolutely no idea!
全然、わかん、わかん、わかん、あー！！！
I don't get it, don't get it, don't get it at all, ahhh!!!
膨らんじゃった やばおぴ加減
It's swollen up, this crazy condition.
最高潮のをくれてやる
I'll give you my absolute climax.
好きって言葉で踊って
Dance with the word "love",
迎え撃つから君のアイデンティティティティティーン
and I'll meet your iden-ti-ti-ti-teen!
侮らないで 夢見がちボーイ
Don't underestimate me, dreamy boy.
意外とありなんだって
It's actually quite acceptable.
気づいて妄想フラストレーション
Realize this delusional frustration,
もう暴走止まらない ギガンティック
my rampage won't stop, it's gigantic!
指切りげんまん
Pinky promise,
嘘ついたら４０ピストン
if you lie, forty pistons!
みだれ打ち！
Flurry of waving!
ラプくんの時代が来た！
Lapu-kun's era has arrived!
ショタかわちーよ！
Shota Lapu-kun is so cute!
ラプくん、輝いてる！
Lapu-kun, you're shining!
最後まで輝いて！
Keep shining till the very end!
さすがに先輩をファン扱いするのはどうかと思いますよ？
I think treating your senior like a fan is a bit questionable, don't you think?
いや、ノエルさんはファンでしょ！ファンっていうか、ママになろうとしてる人…？
No way, Noel-san is definitely a fan! Or rather, someone who wants to become my mom...?
とにかく、めっちゃ盛り上がってましたやん！
Anyway, she was super hyped up, wasn't she?!
てかてか、お姉さんといえば、ホロライブって学校みたいじゃない？
By the way, speaking of big sisters, don't you think Hololive is like a school?
学校？
A school?
学校のみんなのアイドル…そらさん
Everyone's school idol... Sora-san.
隣のクラスの留学生…キアラさん
The exchange student in the next class... Kiara-san.
凛とした清楚な先輩…AZKiさん
The dignified and pure senior... AZKi-san.
部活の先輩お姉さま…ネリッサ
The older sister from the club activity... Nerissa.
クールビューティーな先生…クロニー
The cool-beauty teacher... Kronii.
そして、同じクラスにいる、うるさい幼馴染の同級生…いろは
And my noisy childhood friend in the same class... Iroha.
そうだ！これをライブでやれば、盛り上がること間違いなし！
I know! If we do this in a concert, it'll definitely be a hit!
そうと決まれば早速突撃だー！
Now that that's decided, let's charge right in!
次から次へとすごい行動力だ…
Her ability to take action one thing after another is amazing...
いろはー！
Iroha!
うん？なんでござるか！？
Hm? What is it degozaru?!
ライブでやりたい曲あるんだけど、見ててくんない？
There's a song I want to do for the concert, could you watch it?
見る？どういうことでござる？
Watch? What do you mean by that, degozaru?
そう！見るだけ！
Yes! Just watch!
やっぱり幼馴染と言えば、いつでも見守ってくれる存在だからね…
After all, childhood friends are always there to look over you...
ただそこにいるだけで良い、そばにいてくれるだけ、その温かさが染みるんだ保存
Just being there is enough, just being by my side, that warmth touches my heart.
え…なんか気持ち悪いでござる…
Uh... that's kind of creepy, degozaru...
いいからいいから！さ、行くぞー！
Don't worry about it! Now, let's go!
え？
Eh?
なにこれ？
What is this?
な... なにこれ？
Wh-What is this?
な、な、な、なにこれ？
W-W-W-What is this?
え？
Eh?
何？
What?
え？
Eh?
ラプ様？
Lapu-sama?
お、お？
Oh, oh?
おー
Oh...
お？
Oh?
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
とりあえずさ、気になってるあの娘
To start with, that girl I'm curious about...
きみにドッキドッキめっきめっきスマイル
gives you a pounding, peeling smile!
いやいやいや別に好きとかそんなんじゃないよ
No, no, no, it's not like I actually like her or anything!
ただちょっと、ちょっとちょっとちょっと
It's just that, just a little, little, little, little...
目、追っかけてるだけだってば！
my eyes are just chasing after her, I tell you!
きみに結構めろめろなんだってば
I'm telling you, I'm pretty head over heels for you!
勉強も全然頭に入ってこなくてマズイじゃん
Even studying won't go into my head at all, this is bad!
きみにインスパイア_
Inspired by you!
吐きそう…！
I'm gonna barf...!
この罰ゲームの恥ずい真真、これで終わり？みんなが直接、本人に言ってきます！
Is this embarrassing punishment game all? I'm going to tell them directly!
こわいって！
That's scary!
やべえ！
Oh crap!
そういうことでござるか！
So that's what this is about, degozaru!
違う、ライブ！
No, it's a concert!
ライブ？
A concert?
違う！
No!
やめろ！やめろっつってんだろ！
Stop! I told you to stop!
あ、いいんだ。
Oh, it's fine.
ピピッとボム　増す理性にシンパシー
Beeping bomb, sympathy for growing rationality!
乗ってくてくの波にダイダイ大炸裂
Riding on the walking wave, orange-orange big explosion!
なかなか、なか、なか、なかドキッとしちゃう
Quite, q-q-quite a pounding inside!
きみの、きみの、きみの、きみの、きみの、きみの、きみ
You, you, you, you, you, you, you!
きみ、きみ、もっときみ、きみ、ちょっときみ、きみ、きみ、きみ、A B C D E F Gっ、と
You, you, more of you, you, a bit of you, you, you, you, A-B-C-D-E-F-G-to!
我慢、我慢、我慢できない
I can't bear, bear, bear it!
したしたしゅんき聞いて、そっと、こら、こら、もう
Listen to the youthful times, softly, hey, hey, geez!
お、お、怒らしちゃダメか。え？
Oh, I shouldn't make them angry? Eh?
さ、さ、3年間の、お、お、お、幼馴染の、は、は、恥ずい写真、先輩
Th-Th-Three years of, ch-ch-childhood friend's, em-em-embarrassing pictures, senior!
そんなに急に近づけられたら、もうのけぞる、のけぞる、のけぞる、のけぞる！
If you bring it close so suddenly, I'll bend back, bend back, bend back, bend back!
こうして全員のスタディきらめきして スタート。センチ寄ったら最高。見ちゃった最高！
Like this, everyone's study glitter sparkles, start! Coming a centimeter closer is the best, I saw it, it's the best!
じ、じっと見てるでござるよ
I-I'm watching closely, degozaru...
みだれ打ち、A・K・A・ご奉仕
Flurry of waving, A.K.A. service!
自分でやるんかい
You're doing it yourself?!
お、お肉の生姜焼き
G-Ginger pork!
先輩、天狗、好物
Senior, tengu, favorite food!
上に行って、下に行って
Going up, going down!
バイアル自乗して出した少し
Squaring the vial, I let out a little!
このシチュエーション、止められない本能、俺の...
This situation, an unstoppable instinct, my...
刺激的オトコ
stimulating guy!
ど、どっちを選ぶの？
Wh-Which one will you choose?
どっちを選ぶの？
Which one will you choose?
決めなさいよ！
Decide already!
そう、そうだよ！お、お、イマジナリーお姉さん、と、こい！
C-Come on, imaginary big sisters!
どっちも選べない！ごめん！
I can't choose either! I'm sorry!
すみませんでしたーー！
I am so sorry!!!
ピピッとボム　増す理性にシンパシー
Beeping bomb, sympathy for growing rationality!
乗ってくてくのブレーキ、しぬけ上がれ
Riding on the walking brake, rising up!
ダメ、ダメ、ダメ、ダメ、ダメ、ダメ、食らっちゃう
No, no, no, no, no, no, I'm gonna take the hit!
俺の、俺の、俺の、俺の、俺の、俺の、ファッキン
My, my, my, my, my, my, f-f-f-fucking...
恋して、恋して、もっと恋して、恋して、ちょっと恋して、恋して、恋して、A B C D E F Gっ、と
Fall in love, love, love more, love a bit, love, love, A-B-C-D-E-F-G-to!
立て引いてちょっと、引いて、やっぱ、危険
Put it up, draw back a bit, draw back, as expected, danger!
ピピの、したした、年頃
Beeping, dripping age!
俺、そっと、こら、こら、のちょっと
Me, softly, hey, hey, just a little...
ちょっと男子！
Hey, you boys!
ねえ、ちょっと男子！見せて、ちょっと男子！
Hey, you boys! Show me, you boys!
ちょっと男子！？
You boys?!
ちょっと男子！ねえ、ちょっと男子！見せて、ちょっと男子！あと、おら、やってる！
You boys! Hey, you boys! Show me, you boys! Also, hey, I'm doing it!
いろは！
Iroha!
え、え、何々？
Eh, eh, what is it?
手、手、手、手を、合わせて、ください！
Pl-Pl-Pl-Please put your hands together!
あ、合せる、合せる！
Ah, putting them together, together!
そうそうそう、いいよいいよ、おお、おお
Yes, yes, yes, good, good, oh, oh!
3、2、1...
3, 2, 1...
はーー！
Haa!
手を、合わせてください！はい、みんな、元気に、いただきます！
Please put your hands together! Yes, everyone, with high energy, let's eat!
いきます！
Here I go!
さようなら
Goodbye!
1、2、3、4
One, two, three, four!
2、2、3、4
Two, two, three, four!
先生、皆さん、おピンクです！
Teacher, everyone, I'm pink!
元気すぎるだろ…
She's way too energetic...
インスタ映え まつり 青春 青春
Instagrammable festival, youth, youth!
のってってってって 脳内ミッション
Get on it, get on it, brain mission!
だいだい大惨事 なかなかなかなか
Usually a disaster, quite a lot, quite a lot!
バイバイ危機一髪
Bye-bye close call!
君の 君の 君の 君の バッキューン！
Your, your, your, your, BANG!
ミスミスティ ミスミスティ もっとミスミスティ
Miss Misty, Miss Misty, more Miss Misty!
ちゃんとミスミスティ ミスミスティ ミスミスティ A B C D E F G
Properly Miss Misty, Miss Misty, Miss Misty, A B C D E F G!
がまんがまん ちょっとがまん やっぱりがまんできない
Patience, patience, a little patience, after all I can't hold back!
し・た・し・た・し思春期
P-u-p-e-r-ty!
C-U-T-E-U-H-I-G-K!
不穏なBGMに負けるな…大丈夫そう？
Don't lose to the ominous BGM... Is she going to be okay?
あ、最後までね。お疲れ様です！
Ah, until the end. Thanks for your hard work!
きそ…お疲れ様です…
So tough... Thanks for your hard work...
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
あ、
Ah,
マジでいろはすビジネスでよかったー…
I'm so glad Irohasu is just business...
義務、義務…
Duty, duty...
バイバイ
Bye-bye.
じゃあね、帰るね
See ya, I'm going home.
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
ねえねえ！プロデューサーの好みってどんな人なん？
Hey, hey! What kind of person is the Producer's type?
え～…
Uh...
ほら、ホロライブっていろんな人いるじゃん？
You know, Hololive has all kinds of people, right?
しゅぴしゅわー、すぅの充電足りてるー？水宮すうだよー！
Shubishuwa~, is Su's charge enough? I'm Su Mizumiya!
わっしょーい！ホロライブの清楚担当！みんなのアイドル、夏色まつりでーす！
Wasshoi! In charge of purity in Hololive! Everyone's idol, Matsuri Natsuiro!
みなさん、待ったかねー？ホロックスの女幹部、鷹嶺ルイと申しまーす！
Did everyone wait? HoloX's female executive, Lui Takane here!
はーい、皆様こんらみー。ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
Hi everyone, Kon-Lamy! The face is liver of Hololive 5th gen, Lamy Yukihana!
Good evening! My cute students, choco-on!
ホロライブ2期生、悪魔のバーチャル保健医、癒月ちょこです。ちょこーん！
Hololive 2nd gen, demon virtual school nurse, Choco Yuzuki! Choco-on!
Ahoy! ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンですぅー！
Ahoy! Hololive 3rd Gen, Captain of the Houshou Pirates, Marine Houshou!
みなさんとても魅力的ですよ？
Everyone is very charming, you know?
いやいや、そういうんじゃないでしょ
No, no, that's not what I mean!
いやあ…仕事ですからね
Well... it's work, after all.
ホロライブの方で…とかはないですよ
There is nothing like that with Hololive members...
ふーん
Hmm...
ただ、最近の趣味といえば…
However, if we talk about my recent hobby...
え…
Eh...
いや…それは…流石に…すごい趣味してるな…
No... that... as expected... that's quite a hobby...
この人に言われたくないな…
I don't want to hear that from you...
あ！こんな時間じゃん！我が輩ちょっとこのあと用事あるんで、じゃ！
Ah! Look at the time! I've got something to do after this, so bye!
初めて呼んじゃったぜ…
I called them for the first time...
やべぇ、高かった…
Gosh, it was expensive...
でも可愛かったから、いっか。ジャケットとか、クリーニングしちゃった
But since she was cute, it's fine. I even got my jacket dry-cleaned,
着ちゃった
and wore it...
あっ
Ah!
え？よし
Eh? Okay.
え？
Eh?
これですか？
Is it this?
写真と違う気がするんですけど…
She looks different from the picture though...
え？
Eh?
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！
Change, change, change!
ノーサンキュー！
No thank you!
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！
Change, change, change!
ノーサンキュー！
No thank you!
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！
Change, change, change!
ノーサンキュー！
No thank you!
それじゃちょっと 息抜きでもしましょうかって感じで
How about we take a little breather? With that kind of vibe,
チラシの番号にTEL
I called the number on the flyer.
たまたまドンピシャで気に入った子がいたんで
By chance, there was a girl who was exactly my type,
胸の大きさをチョイス
so I chose her breast size.
髪型ショートで 攻めるのが得意な子
A girl with short hair who is good at being aggressive.
「今からそちらへお送りいたします」
"We will send her over to you right away."
ドアを開けたら 別れた彼女
When I opened the door, it was my ex-girlfriend!
おいおいこいつは いったいなんのジョーダンだ？
Hey, hey, what kind of joke is this?!
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a delivery health and you came!
うつろな目をして立っていた
You were standing there with hollow eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰ってきましたって
"I've returned as your favorite type," you say.
ロミジュリばりの悲劇のにおい
It smells of a tragedy worthy of Romeo and Juliet.
傷つきあわした恋人たち
Lovers who ended up hurting each other.
街頭を見渡して
Looking out over the street lamps,
大声で さあ
with a loud voice, now!
チェンジ チェンジ チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change, change, change! No thank you!
朝のニュースに
In the morning news,
今日はご機嫌どうですか？ 嬢ちゃん
How are you feeling today, missy?
なかなかの塩梅で
Quite in good shape!
隣の部屋 喘ぐ声 大声で
The moans from the next room are so loud...
BPM190で
...at 190 BPM!
細身 綺麗 スレンダー
Slim, beautiful, slender...
たまには私に 従順で 従順で？
Could you be obedient to me for once?
ドアを開けたら 新人 まさかの彼女
When I opened the door, the rookie was... my girlfriend?!
おいおいどんな魔法を使ったってんだよ
Hey, hey, what kind of magic did you pull off?
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a call girl, and it was you who came!
虚ろな目をして立ってたんだ
Standing there with vacant eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプは全部わかっているのよって
"I know all your favorite types," she said.
制服 ギャル ナース OL
School uniform, gyaru, nurse, office lady...
全部登場
...they've all made an appearance!
オプションは頼まない
I won't order any options,
延長もしない
and I won't extend!
行くぞー！せーの！
Here we go! One, two!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
デリヘル呼んだら君が来た
I called a call girl, and it was you who came!
虚ろな目をして立ってたんだ
Standing there with vacant eyes.
あなたの好みのタイプになって帰ってきましたって
"I've come back having changed into your favorite type," she said.
思い出したくもない笑顔が
That smile I don't even want to remember...
トラウマとなって住み着いた
...has settled in as a trauma.
哀心を見下ろして
Looking down with sadness,
絶賛逃亡中
currently on the run!
せーの！
One, two!
チェンジ！チェンジ！チェンジ！ノーサンキュー！
Change! Change! Change! No thank you!
いや、いいんだよ、プロデューサーの好みとか！
No, I don't care about the producer's taste!
聞いたのは、そっちです Bluescreen
You're the one who asked.
ちょっとちょっと、ケンカしてどうしたの！
Wait, wait! What are you fighting about?
あっ、こよちゃん！！！聞いてよー！プロデューサーのやつが～！！！
Ah, Koyo-chan!!! Listen to this! That producer guy...!!!
うんうん
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
それで、あいつがさ～～！！
And then he was like~~!!
そうだね～ラブちゃん辛かったね～
I see~ That must have been tough for you, Lab-chan~
はぁ、ここまでいろんなホロメンと絡んできたけど…
Sigh... I've interacted with so many Hololive members so far, but...
やっぱりこよちゃんが一番だよ！！
Koyo-chan is definitely the best!!
そうだ！今度の我輩の生誕ライブ一緒に出ようよ！こよちゃんと我輩にぴったりな曲があるんだ！
I know! Let's perform together in my upcoming birthday 3D live! I have the perfect song for the two of us!
ライブの出演ね！スケジュール……確認しておくね～！
Performing in your live! I'll... check my schedule!
ありがとー！じゃあまたステージで！！
Thank you! See you on stage then!
（俺、このライブが終わったら……君と……）
(Once this live is over... with you...)
横画面で開始します
[Title: Starting in landscape mode]
時計の針が
The hands of the clock...
12時12分まわるまで
...turn until 12:12.
頭の中
Inside my head...
染められてゆく
...it's getting dyed...
ぴんこすてぃっくLuv
...with Pinkostick Luv.
すれ違うあたり
Passing each other by,
求め目と目が交わるだけで
just wanting our eyes to meet.
宙に浮いてる気分になる
I feel like I'm floating in the air.
でもそんなこと君は知らないし
But you don't know anything about that.
手を繋ぎたい キスをしたい
I want to hold hands, I want to kiss,
君と半径10メートル以内
and stay within a 10-meter radius of you.
でも叶わない だから妄想で
But it won't come true, so in my delusions...
今日も弱気時々の
...today is also filled with occasional shyness...
ぴんこすてぃっくLuv
...Pinkostick Luv.
君のことに一喜一憂だって
Going through ups and downs over you,
好きだから
because I love you.
こっち向いて
Look this way!
待って待って
Wait, wait!
やっぱ向いて
Actually, look at me!
ひとりじめしたいな
I want to keep you all to myself.
こっち向いて
Look this way!
我が儘だって
Even if it's selfish...
わかってるけど
...and I know it is...
だってだってだって
...but, but, but...
面倒だって
...even if it's annoying...
だから何って
...so what?
わかってて恋してるの
I'm in love, and I know it.
サンデーマンデーチューしてギューして 毎日クリンチメイテケキュウチ
Sunday, Monday, kiss me, squeeze me / I'm cleaning up every day, 99
健気さキューティー 一途にウォッチ あっちそっちこっち向いてどっち？！
Being modest, cutie, faithful, watching / Look this way, that way, this way, which way?!
早まる鼓動のBPM 日に日に好きになるSML
My heart rate BPM is quickening / Every day I fall in love with you, SMSL
わかってよなんて自分勝手 やっぱりキッパリとびっきりのラブ
I want you to understand, I'm being selfish / I want a love that is definitive and clear
新鮮なこの想い通い来たる 君に伝えたい"ピンこす"
These fresh feelings are coming through / I want to tell you, "Pinko Stick"
脳内占拠レベルは最強 徹夜ず勉強許して？ご愛嬌
The level of brainwashing is the strongest / I'm studying, please forgive me? It's just a joke
胸のときめきも絶頂 待ちに待った今日
My heart is fluttering, it's at its peak / Today, I've been waiting for this
君とランデブーご一緒 なんて妄想で済ます憂いの性
A rendezvous with you, let's go together / A short-lived romance that ends in my fantasies
こっち向いて、待って待って、やっぱ向いて！
Look this way, wait wait, look this way after all!
恥ずかしいだけど
I'm embarrassed, but
こっち向いて、君の目に映った
Look this way, I feel like the face of me
自分の顔が赤い気がして
Reflected in your eyes is red
目が合って、手が触れた、それだけで
Our eyes met, our hands touched, just that alone
一大事なんだもん
Is a big deal
ねえだって"君のことが"
Hey, because "I love you"
この先がどうしてなの言えないの
Why can't I say the rest?
瞼の裏思い浮かべて
I picture it behind my eyelids
好きだよ好きなのねえ
I love you, I do, hey
想うだけで幸せなの
Thinking about it alone makes me happy
ホントはちょっと切ない
Actually, it's a bit painful
口を出る強がり 見向いて寂しがり
The tough words that come out of my mouth / I want you to see that I'm lonely
実はもう限界 超えてるのだけど
Actually, I'm already at my limit / I've crossed the line, but
言えるはずない 言えるわけない
There's no way I can say it / There's no way I can tell you
臆病なハートに あと押ししてウォンチューミー？
I'll give a push to my cowardly heart / Won't you come to me?
こっち向いて、待って待って、やっぱ向いて！
Look this way, wait wait, look this way after all!
独り占めしたいの
I want you all to myself
こっち向いて、わがままだって
Look this way, I know I'm being selfish
わかってるけどだってだってだってだって
But, but, but, but
目が合って、高鳴って、赤くなって
Our eyes meet, my heart races, I turn red
百面相してるの
I'm having a hundred fantasies
今日だって君のせいで
Even today, because of you
ドキドキ忙しい神様お願い
My heart is busy, God, please
ちょっとでいいから、勇気をください
Just a little bit is fine, give me the courage
カジキマグロ チョー！
Kajiki Maguro! Chow!
プロデューサー、あぁーー！！！
Producer, aaaaah!!!
どうしたんですか？
What's wrong?
こよちゃんにフラれたぁ〜〜
Koyo-chan rejected me!
フラれるとかあるんですね？
I didn't think you could get rejected.
ちくしょう！！！こうなったら！！！
Damn it!!! In that case!!!
嫌な予感がする
I have a bad feeling about this.
誰でもいいから付き合いたーーい！！
I'll go out with anyone, I just want to date!!!
そうなったらもう終わりですよ
If it comes to that, you're doomed.
うるさい！我が輩は、彼女作って幸せになるんだー！！！
Shut up! I'm going to get a girlfriend and be happy!!!
やるぞ…
I'll do it...
緊張する…
I'm nervous...
やってやるぞ…
I'm gonna do it...
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I want to date anyone because it's okay
もう誰でもいいから
I want to date anyone now
男の前では喋れても
I can talk perfectly fine in front of guys
女の前では喋れない
But I can't talk when I'm in front of girls
トラウマだらけの僕の過去
My trauma-littered history
涙なしでは語れない
I cannot recount without a tear in my eyes
「どうして彼女ができないの？」
"Why can't I get a girlfriend?"
僕は素敵だと君は言う
"I think you're a wonderful person" you say to me
「それなら僕と付き合ってよ」
"Then why not go out with me?"
その苦笑いの意味はなに
Why that awkward face?!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
誰でもいいから付き合いたい
I don't care who, somebody go out with me
もう誰でもいいから
Somebody, anybody!
なんで！！！なんでだよーーー！！！
Why?! Why is this happening?!
全員からフラれたぁ〜〜〜！！！
I got rejected by everyone!!!
うーん、このライブ、大丈夫かな
Hmm, I wonder if this live concert is going to be okay...
くそ！もうこうなったら！
Damn it! In that case!
ええ！？なんですかそれ！
What?! What is that?!
この封印を… 解放してやる！！！
I will... release this seal!!!
俺の聖植を… 爆裂させてやる！！！
I will make my sacred plant... explode!!!
うおおおーーー！！！
Uwoooooh!!!
お、おしまいだこのライブは… もはやライブなのかも怪しい所…
This, this concert is doomed... Is this even a live concert anymore...
横画面で開始します
[Screen text: Please start in landscape mode]
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
作詞・作曲：れるりり＆もじゃ
[Song: Sacred Spear Exploding Boy
Lyrics/Composition: Rerulili & Moja]
なんて言うか大きな声で言うことではないかもしれませんが
This might not be something to say out loud, but...
男女に備わったあれとそれ
...that "this" and "that" equipped to boys and girls...
正と乱のいわばあれとそれ
...the so-called "this" and "that" of purity and disorder...
そんなこんで起こるハプニング
...with happenings like this and that...
あっという間に僕のエンディング
...leading to my sudden ending.
誤って悩んで困ってしまって
Apologizing, agonizing, and in a bind...
どうしようって何もできない無常
...asking "what should I do?" in helpless vanity.
0.02ミリの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
The 0.02mm barrier gets so frustrating...
真っ赤なサンシャイン
...my bright red sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
It's your fault I want to insert it right away.
いいじゃんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
Welcoming you with a careless "whatever" attitude, you and I in that heaven...
あ、しまったって思ったってもう遅い
...even if I think "Ah, crap," it's already too late.
Upside inside out.
I defend you.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
愛で返事
...replying with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
待ってこれって僕のせい？
Wait, is this my fault?
生でいいよって言った君のせい？
Is it your fault for saying raw is fine?
そして5分で終わるテストって
And a test that finishes in 5 minutes...
信憑性欠けるもんだって
...lacks any credibility.
しっかり刻まれた十字架に
Firmly nailed to the carved cross,
はりつけられた僕はキリステ
I am cast aside as a sacrifice.
なったって無理ってわかっているって
Knowing full well it's impossible now...
どうしようって何もできない
...wondering what to do, unable to do anything.
0.02ミリの壁がすげー悩ましくなって保存
The 0.02mm barrier gets so distressing...
真っ青なサンシャイン
...my pale blue sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは僕のせい
It's my fault I want to insert it right away.
大丈夫とかそんな気分で甲斐性もないこんな身分で
With a carefree "it's fine" attitude, in this useless social standing...
泣いたって怒ったって後の祭り
...crying or getting angry is crying over spilled milk.
Maximum insertなう。Are you ready?
Maximum insert now. Are you ready?
愛撫ハニー
Love-bite honey,
指噛み白菜
finger-biting,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Sacred Spear Exploding Boy.
愛がfeeling. I've honey.
Love is feeling. I've honey.
You be coming.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
遠い夏の思い出
Distant summer memories...
君の長い髪が揺れる
...your long hair swaying.
待ってこれって僕のせい？
Wait, is this my fault?
中に出してって言った君のせい？
Is it your fault for saying "finish inside"?
そして5分で終わるテストって
And a test that finishes in 5 minutes...
絶対的二元論だって
...is an absolute dualism.
十月十日ばかりの運命を
Over a destiny of just ten months and ten days,
支配している僕は神様に
I, who rules over it, to God...
なれないって無理ってわかっていて
...can never become, knowing it's impossible...
結局何も解決してない
...and in the end, nothing is resolved.
0.02ミリの壁がすげーもどかしくなって
The 0.02mm barrier gets so frustrating...
真っ白なサンシャイン
...my pure white sunshine.
すぐに入れたくなるのは君のせい
It's your fault I want to insert it right away.
いいじゃんとかそんな気分で迎えた君と僕そんなヘブンで
Welcoming you with a careless "whatever" attitude, you and I in that heaven...
あ、しまったって思ったってもう遅い
...even if I think "Ah, crap," it's already too late.
Upside
inside out. I defend you.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
愛で返事
...replying with love.
I'm coming. You're coming.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
Maximum insertなう。Are you ready?
Maximum insert now. Are you ready?
愛撫ハニー
Love-bite honey,
指噛み
finger-biting,
聖槍爆裂ボーイ
Sacred Spear Exploding Boy.
愛がfeeling. I've honey.
Love is feeling. I've honey.
You be coming.
甘噛み Youの髪
A gentle bite, your hair...
いっさいがっさいは
...absolutely everything...
いやぁ、まさか、聖槍でライブ会場壊しちゃうなんて
Wow, I didn't expect the Sacred Spear to actually destroy the live venue.
つい…力を解放してしまった…
I accidentally... unleashed my power...
それにしても、みんなひどくない？吾輩を振るなんて…
But still, isn't everyone so cruel? Dumping me like that...
もうやってらんないよ～
I can't deal with this anymore!
（ここはあの手を使うしかない）
(I have no choice but to use *that* trick.)
ラプラスさん、実は、あの方に来ていただいてます！
Laplus-san, actually, I've invited that person to come over!
あの型？
That type?
ラプくん？どうしたのー？
Lap-kun? What's wrong?
うわっ！？あ、あ、あじゅ姉！？
Whoa?! A-A-Azu-nee?!
まさか、吾輩のために来てくれたの？？？？
No way, did you come here just for me?
当然だよー！だって今日は、ラプくんの誕生日でしょー？
Of course! After all, today is Lap-kun's birthday, right?
あ、やばい、吾輩今日が命日かもしれん…
Ah, oh no, today might be the anniversary of my death...
お誕生日おめでとう！プレゼントは何がいいのかな～？
Happy birthday! I wonder what you'd like for a present?
え！プレゼントってなんでももらえるの？！
What! Can I get anything I want for a present?!
あじゅがあげられるものなら何でも大丈夫だゾ☆
Anything Azu can give you is fine! ☆
えー！！えええ！じゃあーー
No way!! Wh-Wh-Well then—
え？今なんて言ったの？変な音で聞こえなかった！
Eh? What did you say just now? I couldn't hear because of a weird sound!
あれ？
Huh?
なんだこれー！届かないぞ吾輩の願いが！
What is this! My wish won't reach her!
あぶない…危うく配信できないところだった…
That was close... We almost couldn't stream this...
邪魔するなプロデューサーーーーー！！！！！！
Don't get in my way, Producer!!!!
なんか色々大変そうだから… 今日はこの辺で帰るね！
It seems like you're quite busy with various things... I'll head home for today!
今日は本当におめでと～！ ラプくん、また遊ぼうね～
Happy birthday again! Let's play again soon, Lap-kun!
帰るね！
I'm heading home!
今日は本当におめでとう！
Happy birthday today!
ラプくん、また遊ぼうね〜！
Lap-kun, let's hang out again!
あ、あじゅねえ！
Ah, Aju-nee!
あじゅねええええ！！
Aju-neeeee!
え、はい、はい。分かりました！
Yes, yes, I understand!
ラププラスさん！新曲オーディションですって！
Laplus-san! Apparently there's an audition for a new song!
どゆこと！？
What do you mean!?
新曲だけのオーディション大会があって、そこで優勝したら、大型コラボですって！
There's an audition competition with only new songs, and if you win, you get a massive collaboration!
今すぐ曲準備します！
I'll prepare the song right away!
ダンスレッスンいれますね！
I'll book dance lessons!
今から新曲？ダンスレッスン？
A new song starting now? Dance lessons?
ま、間に合うのそれ？もうライブまでちょっとしかないよ？
W-will we make it in time? There's barely any time left before the concert!
間に合わせてください！
Please make it in time!
もしオーディションに合格したら、大型コラボなんですよ！
If we pass the audition, it's a major collaboration!
えー！吾輩もう疲れたんですけど！！！
What! I'm already exhausted!!!
大型コラボってなんなの！！
What even is this "major collaboration" anyway!?
それはまだ、秘密です。
That is still a secret.
なんでだよおおおお！！！
Why the hell not!?
はあ…はあ…はあ…
Haah... haah... haah...
体力ないって言ってるのに、走り込み…？
Even though I told you I have no stamina, I'm road running...?
だからこその走り込みです！
That's exactly why you need to do roadwork!
この筋トレ、本当に意味あるのー！？
Is this muscle training actually serving any purpose!?
だっ、はあ…はあ…あぁぁ…
Ugh... haah... haah...
よし、良い感じです！
Alright, looking good!
ラプラスさん！本番前に行きましょう！
Laplus-san, let's head out before the real deal!
あの方の元へ！
To that person's place!
あ、あの方！？
T-that person!?
あーよし、行こう！
Ah, alright, let's go!
チョコ先生ーー！！
Choco-sensei!
あら、いらっしゃい、ラプちゃん。
Oh, welcome, Lap-chan.
どれにするの？
Which one will you choose?
うーん、悩んじゃうよね。
Hmm, it's hard to make up your mind, isn't it?
うーん、わかる、わかる。
Hmm, I know, I know.
答えは1つじゃないからね。
Because there isn't just one right answer.
ラプちゃん真剣に考えてるのね。
Lap-chan, you're thinking so hard about it.
ん？全部ちゃんと見たいの？
Hmm? You want to see them all properly?
じゃあ、皆さんお待ちかねの、グッズ情報よ！
Then, here is the merchandise info you've all been waiting for!
ラプちゃーん！
Lap-chaaaan!
はーい！はいはいはーい！
Yeees! Yes, yes, yeees!
ラプラス・ダークネス、誕生日記念2026グッズ！
Laplus Darkness Birthday Celebration 2026 Merchandise!
順番に紹介していきます！
Let's introduce them one by one!
じゃん！まずはこちら、カードアルバム！
Tah-dah! First up is this, the card album!
特典の、あの、チェキ風ブロマイドカードとか、ホロカとかを収納できるアルバムです！
This is an album where you can store bonus items, like the instax-style photo cards or HoloCards!
えっと、めっちゃ久しぶりに黒野先生が、え、我が輩のママね。黒野ママが…
And, for the first time in a really long time, Kurono-sensei... well, my illustrator mama, Kurono-mama...
え、描き下ろしてくれました、イラスト！
...drew a brand new illustration!
イェーイ！
Yay!
めっちゃ可愛い！
It's so cute!
はい、でしょ？
Right?
いや、このアルバムをぎゅっとしてるのが、また良いよね。
And it's so nice how you're hugging this album.
そう、でしょ？これもちゃんと、あのアルバムをぎゅっとしてるんですよ。写ってるやつを。
Exactly! This illustration is actually hugging that exact album.
じゃあ、これ買ったら、ラプちゃんがぎゅっとしたアルバムが手に入るってこと？
So if we buy this, does that mean we get an album hugged by Lap-chan?
え！？それはあの、商品法…？それ、刑訴…、刑訴…
Huh!? That would be, um, Product Liability Law...? Or, Code of Criminal Procedure...?
刑訴的にいきます！
...we might be violating criminal procedure!
二つ目はこちら！興奮ボイスキーホルダー！
The second item is this! The Excited Voice Keychain!
え、毎回お馴染みの、撮り下ろしボイスが、が６種類入ったキーホルダーです！
It's our usual keychain featuring 6 newly recorded voice lines!
え、押すと声が出ます。いつも通り。今回もしろこ先生の描き下ろしです！
Pressing it plays the audio, as usual. Once again, illustrated by Shiroko-sensei!
メロメロな表情をした、オリジナルの、デフォルメ姿です！
An original chibi design showing a totally lovesick expression!
押すと声が出る。
Pressing it plays a voice.
はい。
Yes.
へえ〜。
Ooh...
どこを押すのかな〜？
I wonder where you press it~?
三つ目は、三つ目はこちら！
The third... the third item is this!
「ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみ」です！
The "Baby Laplus Plushie"!
えっと、おしゃぶりを加えて、ベビーウェアを着て寝ている、我が輩のぬいぐるみでございます。
It's a plushie of yours truly sucking on a pacifier and sleeping in baby clothes.
え、めっちゃ可愛いー！
Ah, that's incredibly cute!
私もぎゅっとしたーい！
I want to cuddle it too!
ちょ、チョコせん…先生そんな…
W-wait, Choco-sen... sensei, please don't... Jacks...
ぎゅっとしたーい。いつでも…
I want to hug it... any time...
あ、いいにおいする。
Ah, it smells so good.
あ、やめてください！
Ah, please stop!
本当に…もうまずい、まずい。
Seriously... this is getting dangerous.
四つ目はこちら！
The fourth item is this!
「ばぶラプラスぬいぐるみ」を包めるハンカチです！
The swaddling handkerchief that can wrap up the "Baby Laplus Plushie"!
さっきのぬいぐるみをね、包めて、あとは普通にハンカチとしても使えます。
You can wrap up the plushie from before in it, or you can just use it as a regular handkerchief.
あ、じゃあ、おくるみとして使えるってことね！
Ah, so it can be used as a swaddle!
そうです！
That's right!
可愛い。
Cute.
で、デカめ、デカめです、これ。こんなしかないですけど、我が輩の周り。
It's on the larger side. Though it's only about this big for me.
そして最後に、フルセット購入特典として、三嶋くろねママ描き下ろしのチェキ風ブロマイドカードが付いてきます！
And finally, as a full set purchase bonus, you get an instax-style photo card illustrated by Mishima Kurone-mama!
はい、そして数量限定バージョンは、はい、書きます。サインを！
Yes, and for the limited-quantity version, I will hand-write my signature!
直筆サインと、複製メッセージが入ってます！
It includes a hand-written signature and a printed message!
通常バージョンは 箔押しの 複製サインと メッセージが 入ってるよ。
For the regular version, a foil-stamped replica signature and message are included!
この配信のあとに 販売開始だから、
They will go on sale right after this stream ends,
みんな！ よろしくねー！
so everyone, please look forward to it!
おねがいしますー！
Please support us!
はい、以上グッズ紹介なんですけど、
Yes, that concludes the merch introduction...
チョコ先生、ありがとうございました！
Choco-sensei, thank you very much!
ええ、こちらこそ！
You're very welcome!
ありがとうございます。これからちょっと、オーディションなんで、新曲の。
Thank you! I actually have an audition next for my new song.
おっ。
Oh!
がんばって。
Good luck!
応援してるね、ラプちゃん、がんばって！
I'll be cheering you on, Lapu-chan! Do your best!
がんばります！ ありがとう！
I'll do my best! Thank you!
がんばれー！
Do your best!
あっ、お姉さま！
Ah, Onee-sama!
あの、今日ライブなのに、吾輩お風呂入ってないんですけど、
Um, even though we have a live show today, I haven't taken a bath...
お願いがあってぇ、
But I have a request...
あの、耳、舐めて欲しいです！
Um, I want you to lick my ears, please!
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~!
世の中のお姉さまに捧ぐ
Dedicated to the Onee-samas of the world.
（あ、お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡）
(Ah, Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡)
起きたら耳元で囁いて
Whisper into my ear when I wake up.
（あ、お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡）
(Ah, Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡)
胸元に滴るその汗を
The sweat dripping down your chest...
「吾輩のお紅茶に入れてゴックンゴックンしたい！」
"I want to put it in my tea and gulp it down!"
ツノツノツノ掴んでちょうだい
Grab my horns, grab my horns, grab them!
ハンドル代わりにをををを！
Use them as a steering wheel, oh, oh, oh, oh!
あっ！あぁ！お姉さまと、視聴者の皆様！
Ah! Ah! Onee-sama, and the viewers!
こんな歌ライブで歌って、ごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry for singing a song like this at a live show!
あっ、お仕置き！お仕置きください！
Ah, punishment! Please punish me!
しっぽから手ぇ突っ込んで、ガタガタ言わせてください、ツノを！
Stick your hand in from my tail and make my horns rattle!
あっ、お姉さま今日、ニーハイですか！
Ah, Onee-sama, are those thigh-highs today?!
盛り上がってきましたねー！
We're really getting hyped, aren't we?!
えっ、お姉さま！あっ、お姉さま来ちゃう！
Eh, Onee-sama! Ah, Onee-sama is coming!
あっ、お姉さま！あぁっ、お世話になっておりま～～す！！！...
Ah, Onee-sama! Ah, thank you for always taking care of me!!!
ありがたや たや ありがたや
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
おいでなすってお姉さま！
Come over here, Onee-sama!
雑魚雑魚言ってください
Please call me small fry, small fry!
残さず飲み込むゾ
I'll swallow it all without leaving a drop!
愛のムチムチ 愛の鞭
Love's whip-whip, love's whip!
お願いなぶってお姉さま！
Please whip me, Onee-sama!
キモくてごめんなさい
I'm sorry for being gross.
ありのままでキャストオフ
As I am, cast off!
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~!
刮目せよ！YMDはもう古い！！！
Pay close attention! YMD is already old!
時代はYSOだ！
The era of YSO is here!
YSOとは何か！？
What does YSO stand for?!
そう！やたらセクシーなお姉さまだ！！！
Yes! \"Excessively Sexy Onee-sama\"!!!
YSO! YSO!
YSO!!!!!
YY YY YY
YY YY YY YSO YY YY
YY YY YSO YY YY YSO
お姉さま！お姉さま！
Onee-sama! Onee-sama!
やたらセクシーなお姉さま！
Excessively sexy Onee-sama!
ほんわかドジっ子 姉御肌
Easygoing airhead, older sister type.
クーデレ ツンデレ 小悪魔系
Kuudere, Tsundere, little devil type.
いろんな姉が、いるけれど
There are all kinds of sisters, but...
あらあらウフフが優勝です
the \"ara ara ufufu\" type is the absolute best!
もち肌！（ぷにぷに）太もも？（スリスリ）
Soft skin! (Squishy) Thighs? (Rub rub)
ギューして！（ムニムニ）居なけりゃ？（無理無理ぃぃぃ）
Hug me! (Squeeze squeeze) If you're not here? (No way!)
あぁん、お姉様がいない世界なんて
Ah, a world without Onee-sama...
耐えられないでちゅううう！！！！
I can't endure it, chuuuuuu!!!!
そうして、吾輩は、赤ちゃんになった。
And so, I became a baby.
なでなで、よしよしされる幸せな世界。
A happy world where I'm patted and spoiled.
今日もまた、お姉さまの太ももに顔をうずめ、
Today again, burying my face in Onee-sama's thighs...
涎を垂らす。これが、人生なのだ。
drooling. This is life.
キモく 正しく 美しく
Grossly, correctly, beautifully.
おいでって言って お姉さま！
Say \"Come here\", Onee-sama!
抱っこ 抱っこ してください
Hug me, hug me, please.
本能が 剥き出しゾ
My instincts are completely exposed!
脚のムチムチ 胸のムチ
Thick legs, thick breasts.
失礼します お姉さま！
Excuse me, Onee-sama!
全裸で ごめんなさい
I'm sorry for being naked.
ありのままで キャストオフ
As I am, cast off!
愛してます お姉さま♡
I love you, Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
やたらセクシーなお姉さま♡
Excessively sexy Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
すーはーすーはーお姉さま♡
Suu-haa suu-haa Onee-sama ♡
お姉さま♡あぁお姉さま♡
Onee-sama ♡ Ah, Onee-sama ♡
お・ね・え・さ・ま～～！
O-ne-e-sa-ma~~!
あっ、バブー。
Ah, baboo.
ということで新曲を披露させていただきました。
And with that, I got to perform my new song.
タイトルは...
The title is...
お姉様...
"Oneesama...
お姉様ラヴコールです。
Oneesama Love Call."
ちゃんと「お姉様」の後にハートが付くやつです。
It's the one with a heart right after "Oneesama".
ビートまりおさんとまろさんに作ってもらいました。
It was made for me by Beat Mario-san and Maro-san.
依頼した時は
When I requested it,
「最近のラプラスさんを見てたら楽しく作れました」と言ってくれました。
they said, "Watching Laplus lately made it fun to create!"
とんでもない曲になっちゃったぜ。
It ended up becoming an outrageous song!
収録の時も、あ、これ後でリリースされるんですけど、
Even during recording—ah, this will be released later—
収録する時もね。
but when we were recording...
「もっとキモく！もっと内なるお姉様への想いを
they told me, "Make it creepier!
込めながら歌ってください」とか言われて、
Sing while putting more of your inner feelings for Oneesama into it!"
あんなディレクションは初めてでした。
That was the first time I'd ever received direction like that.
そんな曲がこの後、MVがね、
And that song's MV...
私のこのチャンネルでプレミア公開されますよ。
...will be premiering right after this on my channel!
そして、5月25日なんですけど、
And even though today is May 25th,
明日26日に日付が変わった瞬間に、この曲がリリースされてしまいます。
the moment the date changes to tomorrow, the 26th, this song will be released!
さらに何と！
And what's more!
これはね、サムネにも重大告知って感じで書いたんですけど、
I wrote "Major Announcement" on the thumbnail, almost like clickbait...
何と！ついに！
but finally!
私、ラプラス・ダークネス、1人で初めての
my very first solo...
アルバムが発売されるぜ！イェーイ！
album is being released! Yay!
いや、何か一年に一曲しかオリジナル曲出さなかったのに、
Man, I used to release only one original song a year,
去年狂ったようにオリ曲出して、
but last year I released them like crazy.
今年も出して、アルバムが出せるように
And after releasing more this year,
なるなんてね、感慨深いでございます。
being able to release an album is deeply moving for me.
そして、何と今回は2種類出るんだけど、
And there will be two versions available!
1つ目がね、
First is...
ラプラス・ダークネス 1st Album 『ラブ様アーティスト化計画』
Laplus Darknesss 1st Album, "Lapu-sama Artistification Project"---
「高いやつ」！
"The Expensive One"!
ということで、「高いやつ」です。
So, that's "The Expensive One."
で、もう1つが、
And the other one is...
『ラブ様アーティスト化計画』
"Lapu-sama Artistification Project"---
「安いやつ」！
"The Cheap One"!
ということで、お金を持っている
So we have the album for grown-up friends
大きなお友達用のアルバムと、
who have money...
お金ちょっとママにお願いして「ママ買って」っておねだりできそうな値段の、
and a reasonably priced one where you can ask, "Mom, please buy this for me!"
おねだりできそうな値段の、
with a price you can beg for...
ホロライブで出てるアルバムだと一番安いんじゃない？っていうくらいの、
It might actually be the cheapest album ever released in Hololive—
「安いやつ」の2種類があるよ。
"The Cheap One"! There are two versions!
この配信のあとから、ホロライブ公式ショップで予約開始だから、
Pre-orders start on the official Hololive shop right after this stream,
みんな予約してね！
so make sure to pre-order!
詳しくはホームページをチェック！
For details, check the website!
さっき披露した新曲も、もちろんアルバムに入るぜ。
Naturally, the new song I just performed will be included in the album too!
さあ、新曲オーディションは果たした。
Well, I've finished the new song audition.
あとは結果待つだけなんで、
Now we just wait for the results.
おやすみ、バイバイ。
Goodnight, bye-bye.
お疲れ。
Good job.
もし優勝したらね、褒美って言ってたんだ。何だろうな。
If I win, they promised me a reward. I wonder what it'll be.
やりましたね！優勝ですよ！
We did it! You won!
さすがにレッスンとか急すぎたって〜もうへとへと。
As expected, the lessons were too sudden... I'm exhausted.
はい、分かりました！ラプラスさん...
Yes, understood! Laplus-san...
お？
Oh?
今すぐいきますよ！大型コラボの現場へ！！！
We're going right now! To the site of the giant collaboration!!!
え？なに？え、なになに？どこ行くの〜？？？
Eh? What? Wait, what? Where are we going~???
みんなー！こんばんはー！
Everyone! Good evening!
来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming!
短い時間だけど、一緒に楽しもうね！
It's a short time, but let's have fun together!
今日は、特別なゲストが来てくれています！
Today, we have a very special guest!
ホロライブの、ラプラス・ダークネスさんです！
From Hololive, it's Laplus Darknesss-san!
リ、リナ... リナミお姉さん！
Ri-Rina... Rinami-oneesan!
ほ、本当に...
I-Is it really...
え、あ、本当に。
Oh, yes, really.
あ、本当にリナミお姉さんだ！
Ah, it really is Rinami-oneesan!
本物、本物なんですか？
Are you really the real deal?
はい！はじめまして！
Yes! Nice to meet you!
あ、はじめまして。
Ah, nice to meet you.
今日はご一緒できて光栄です！
I'm honored to be here with you today!
あ、はい...
Ah, yes...
何て呼んだらいいですか？
What should I call you?
あ、あのお、敬語、敬語やめてください、あの...
Ah, please drop the polite speech...
吾輩のことは、あの、ラプくんって呼んでください。
Please call Wagahai "Lap-kun."
ラプくん。
Lap-kun.
吾輩も、あの、リナミお姉さんって呼んでもいいですか？
Can Wagahai call you Rinami-oneesan too?
もちろん！
Of course!
リナミお姉さんって呼んでくれると嬉しいな！
I'd be so happy if you called me Rinami-oneesan!
ラプくん？
Lap-kun?
はい... ふふ、リナミお姉さん...
Yes... Hehe, Rinami-oneesan...
ラプくん？
Lap-kun?
はい！
Yes!
今日は、私の曲を披露させてもらうんだけど...
I'll be performing my song today...
ラプくんも、会場を盛り上げるために...
and to help pump up the venue, Lap-kun...
ちょっとだけ一緒に参加してくれるんだよね？
will be participating with me a little bit, right?
はい！あの、恐縮です！
Yes! I'm so humbled!
あの、本当は、こんな近くで見れるだけでも嬉しいんですけど...
Actually, just being able to see you this close makes me happy...
微力ながら参加させていただきます！
but I will do my best to participate!
うふふ、一緒に共演できて嬉しいよ！
Hehe, I'm so glad we can perform together!
素敵なライブになるといいね。
I hope it turns out to be a wonderful live performance.
はい！
Yes!
それじゃあ、早速1曲披露させてもらおうかな！
Then, I'll go ahead and perform my first song!
ラプくん、準備はいい？
Lap-kun, are you ready?
はい！もちろん、あの、いきます！準備します！あ、いきます！
Yes! Of course! I'm ready, let's go! I'll get ready! Let's do this!
みんなも一緒に楽しもうね！
Everyone, let's have fun together too!
それでは1曲目、
Now then, for the first song...
聴いてください。
Please listen.
I know I know 放課後
I know, I know, after school...
今日は少しだけ遠回りして帰っちゃお
today, I think I'll take the long way home.
全然始まらない物語を見ているような気分
I feel like I'm watching a story that never starts.
淡々な君にお知らせします
Just to let indifferent you know,
このままいけばエンドロールで憂鬱
at this rate, the end credits will be depressing.
つ・つ・そ・そ・その目
Y-Y-Y-Y-Your eyes,
て・て・つないで
h-h-holding hands,
い・い・いろ
c-c-colors...
そう、その目、まあ
Yeah, those eyes, well...
ちょっとおでこ貸して　熱でもあるのかって
Let me borrow your forehead to check for a fever.
ちゅって、ちゅって、きゅって、きゅって、きゅっと
Mwah, mwah, squeeze, squeeze, tight!
私の「Q」を受け取ってよ
Please receive my "cue"!
超えて急展開見てみたいの
I want to see a rapid development beyond this.
私、このモーションじゃお留守番でしょ
With this motion, I'll just be left behind, right?
36度 U・B・Uな君に交渉
Negotiating with you, who are 36 degrees and innocent.
もうちょい私にお熱をあげてほしいのです
I want you to give me a bit more fever.
君のせいで
Because of you,
私は一体
what on earth
何度の...？はい、どうぞ！
is my temperature...? Okay, here you go!
ここからは君の番
From here on, it's your turn.
うまく言おう
Say it well.
照れたりしないで
Don't be shy.
ちょっと不自然くらいじゃなきゃ
Unless it's a little unnatural,
恋なんてそう始まりやしないもの
love like this won't even begin!
言い訳は横に置いて
Put excuses aside.
弾む気持ちはちょっとハイな
My bouncing heart is a little high.
熱いラブにうなされてみない？
Why not let yourself be struck by a hot love fever?
基本の基本　恋 of サンバ　チャ・チャ・チャ
The basics of basics: Samba of love, cha-cha-cha!
挑戦チャレンジ　読めぬメッセージ
Take on the challenge, unreadable message.
さりげないタッチ
A casual touch...
翻訳すればすべてが　つまり「I love you」
If translated, everything means "I love you."
頭で考えずに脊髄反射で応えて
Don't think, just respond with your spinal reflex.
脳の温度上がらない予想　あとちょっと
The brain temperature won't rise, I predict. Just a bit more,
もう一歩
one more step.
3、2、1で　はい！
At three, two, one, yes!
やればできる子　撫でて　よろしく
I'm a good girl if I try, so pat me, please!
36度2分　うぶな君に交渉
Negotiating with innocent you at 36.2 degrees.
とうに自覚しててもモタモタなシチュエーションね
Even if you've realized it, it's such a slow situation.
抜け出して
Escape it,
異次元手と手
hold hands out of this world,
素敵をいっぱい感じて！はい、どうぞ！
and feel lots of wonderful things! Okay, here you go!
ここからは君の番
From here on, it's your turn.
違うかも　泣き顔見せないで
Maybe it's different, don't show your crying face.
ちょっとくらいの勘違いがなきゃ
Unless there's a little misunderstanding,
恋なんてそう始まりやしないもの
love like this won't even begin!
ラプくん！お誕生日おめでとう！
Lap-kun! Happy Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
一緒に！
Together!
クラップ！
Clap!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ちょっとおでこ貸して　熱でもあるのかって
Let me borrow your forehead to check for a fever.
ちゅって、ちゅって、きゅって、きゅって、きゅっと
Mwah, mwah, squeeze, squeeze, tight!
私の「Q」を受け取ってよ
Please receive my "cue"!
予感、耳も委ねてみたいの
I want to surrender even my ears to this premonition.
私からのモーションじゃ遅すぎるでしょ
With a motion from me, it'll be too slow, right?
36℃ ウブな君に caution!
36°C, caution to you who are naive!
もうちよい私にお熱をあげて欲しいのです
I want you to raise the heat for me a little more.
余裕に見えて
It looks like I have room to spare,
私もいっぱい いっぱいで
but I'm also at my limit...
はい、少々本音を打ち明けちゃう
Yes, I'll reveal a little of my true feelings,
完璧な お姉さんだって
that even as a perfect big sister,
ちょっとくらいの隙がなくちゃ
if there isn't a little opening,
好きになんてなれるはずがないものでしょ？
there's no way you could fall in love, right?
だから君を...
That's why I'm...
“スキ”だらけで待っています
waiting for you with "like" all over,
いつだって
always...
ちょっとhighな熱いloveにうなされてみたい
I want to try being eroded by a slightly high, hot love!
36℃ U・B・U でしたー！
That was 36°C U・B・U!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
最高でしたー！
It was the absolute best!
はっ、ラプくん、ありがとう！
Ah, Lap-kun, thank you!
一緒にパフォーマンスしてくれて嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy you performed with me!
はっ、あの！光栄でした！
Ah... um, it was an honor!
あの、りなみさんのパフォーマンス見れて、もう、光栄でした！
Um, being able to see Rinami-san's performance up close, it was such an honor!
ふふ、ありがとう！
Fufu, thank you!
えっと、今日は次の曲が最後になるんだけど...
Well, the next song is going to be the last one today, but...
えぇー！？早すぎます、まだ見たいです！
Ehh?! That's too fast, I still want to see more!
うー、名残惜しいけど...
Ooh, I hate to say goodbye, but...
次の曲は、みんなにも声を出してほしいな！
for the next song, I want everyone to raise their voices!
一緒に最後まで楽しもうね！
Let's have fun together until the very end!
ラプくんも？
You too, Lap-kun?
もちろんです！もう声枯れるまでやります！
Of course! I'll do it until my voice goes hoarse!
ふふ、ラプくん、
Fufu, Lap-kun,
喉は大事にしてね。
please take care of your throat.
はい！あ、りなみお姉さん！あの、我輩の先輩もどうしてもライブ見たいって言ってるんですけど、呼んでいいですか？
Yes! Ah, Rinami-oneesan! Um, my senior says she really wants to see the live show too. Can I call her?
えっ？誰誰？
Eh? Who is it?
ぜひ！
By all means!
すいません、呼び出します！
Sorry, I'll summon her!
よろしくおねがいします！
Nice to meet you!
さくらみこさん、お会いできて光栄です！
Sakura Miko-san, it's an honor to meet you!
こ、こちらこそです！パフォーマンス楽しみにしてます！
T-The honor is mine! I'm looking forward to your performance!
うれしい！お姉さん頑張っちゃうよ！
I'm so happy! Big sister is going to do her absolute best!
それでは、次の曲、聞いてください！
Now then, please listen to the next song!
回想中 熱くなり お茶いかが？ 冷静に大人で
I'm thinking of something, I'm getting hot, how about some tea? I'm an adult, calmly,
ハートは君にまだ教えずに ご相談チラチラと
I haven't told you about my heart yet, consulting, glancing, glancing...
余裕身につけて
wearing composure,
言う「お相手はyou？」 ドラマのようなことしない女優
saying, "Is the partner you?" I'm not an actress who does things like in dramas.
噛めば噛むほど美味しい lady
The more you chew, the tastier it gets, Lady...
例に甘え方をみせてほしい
I want you to show me how to be spoiled by example.
一緒に歌ってくれる？
Won't you sing with me?
はみ出したい！
I want to overflow!
変われないの
I can't change,
自由型のいい子は好き放題
I'm free-style, a good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅も
I don't know
わからないの
the balance of that either,
優しいふりして ただ焦ってる
pretending to be gentle, just getting impatient...
二人とも、よくできました！
You two did great!
そっと口角上げ 君を
Gently raise the corners of your mouth,
魅せ君を
show me you, you,
そっと心タップ 君を
Gently tap your heart,
あぁ 君を 知りたい
ah, you, you, I want to know.
ラストもお願い！
The last one too, please!
はみ出したい！
I want to overflow!
変われないの
I can't change,
自由型のいい子は好き放題
I'm free-style, a good girl does whatever she wants.
その塩梅も
I don't know
わからないの
the balance of that either,
優しいふりして ただ焦ってる
pretending to be gentle, just getting impatient...
もっと！
More!
はしゃげないの
I can't get excited,
まるっと上手くリードしたいけど
I want to lead perfectly, but
そのボーダーも
I can't even cross
超えらんないの
that border.
そもそもに話 まだ隠して
In the first place, I'm still hiding it,
見つめてる
and I'm staring at you...
clumsy trickでした！
That was clumsy trick!
どうだったかな？
How did you like it?
最高だった！ / 最高です！
It was awesome! / It was amazing!
ラップくんとあんな風に一緒にパフォーマンスすることになるなんて
To think I'd get to perform together with Lap-kun like that...
楽しかったな。
It was so much fun.
よかったら、こっちで一緒に話そうよ。
If you'd like, why don't you come up and talk with me?
えぇ！？ / へっ？
What?! / Eh?
行って来いよ！
Go on up!
いやいやいや、あの、ここが、ここがやっぱり落ち着くんですけど...
No, no, no. I mean, here... this is where I feel most comfortable...
さっきは一緒にステージにいてくれたのに？
But you were on stage with me just a moment ago.
確かに、確かに。
That's true, that's true.
行って来いよ、望まれてるのかな？
Go on up! You're being invited, aren't you?
え、今行きます！待っててください！
Oh, I'll be right there! Please wait for me!
来てくれた！
She's coming!
がんばれ。
Do your best.
急に出てくるからびっくりしちゃったよ。
I was surprised because you suddenly showed up.
すみません、なんか、もう我慢できなくて...
I'm sorry, I just couldn't contain myself any longer...
そんな破天荒なところが、ラップくんの魅力だよね。
That unpredictable side of you is what makes you so charming, Lap-kun.
私も見習いたいよ。
I want to learn from you too.
いや、もう、りなめお姉さんはもうこのままで素敵です！そのままいてください！
No, Riname-oneesan is already wonderful just the way she is! Please stay as you are!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これからもお互い、アイドルとして頑張ろうね。
Let's both keep doing our best as idols from now on.
あ、もう、そ、恐縮です、ありがとうございます。頑張ります！
Ah, that is... I'm so honored, thank you very much. I'll do my best!
またこうやって一緒に共演できたら嬉しいな。
I hope we can share the stage together again like this.
あ、それももう、それも恐れ多すぎます。ありがとうございます！
Ah, that as well... That's way too kind of you. Thank you so much!
今日はありがとう！
Thank you for today!
とっても素敵なミニライブでした！
It was a truly wonderful mini-live!
みんなも楽しんでくれたかな？
I hope everyone had a great time too!
それじゃあまたね！
See you all again!
ラップくんも！
You too, Lap-kun!
え、りなめお姉さん？
Eh, Riname-oneesan...?
お姉さん...
Oneesan...